Guide to the Treasurer, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Financial records, 1897-1966; Accession 1986-A-077
  - Series I
    - 1961-1962
      - Ford/NWA
        - African & Latin American Studies Development #62-00-34-0340 (Box 34, Folder 522)
        - Administrative Expenses #62-00-34-0320 (Box 34, Folder 523)
        - East Asian Studies #62-00-34-2040 (Box 34, Folder 524)
        - Faculty Research #62-00-34-2680 (Box 34, Folder 525)
        - Southeast Asia Studies #62-00-34-7920 (Box 35, Folder 526)
        - Salaries #62-00-34-7050 (Box 35, Folder 527)
        - Russian & East European Studies #62-00-34-7630 (Box 35, Folder 528)
        - Public International Law #62-00-34-7260 (Box 35, Folder 529)
        - International Relations (Box 35, Folder 530)
      - Income & Expenses (Box 35, Folder 531)
      - treasurer's Report (Box 35, Folder 532)
      - treasurer's Reports (Box 35, Folder 533-535)
    - 1962-1963
      - Budget: Comparisons of Approved & Preliminary-Schools & Departments (Box 36, Folder 536)
      - Budget: Analysis of Differences 1962/1963 & 1963/1964 (Box 36, Folder 537)
      - Budget: Comparisons of Approved & Recommended Budgets by Schools & Departments (Box 36, Folder 538)
      - Budgets: Analysis of Differences 1962/1963 & 1963/1964 (Box 36, Folder 539)
      - Budget: Comparison & Actual (Box 36, Folder 540)
      - Budgets: Analysis of Differences Approved & Preliminary, 1962/1963-1963/1964 (Box 36, Folder 541)
      - Budget & Expenditure Accounts (Box 36, Folder 542-543)
      - Budget: Statements & Preliminary Statements (Box 36, Folder 544)
      - Ford/NWA
        - African Studies #62-00-34-0340 (Box 36, Folder 545)
        - Administrative Expenses #62-00-34-0320 (Box 36, Folder 546)
        - General (Box 36, Folder 547)
        - Reconciliations Work Sheets (Box 36, Folder 548)
        - Extra Ford Papers (Box 36, Folder 549)
        - Concilium (Box 36, Folder 550)
        - July 1 Transfers (Box 37, Folder 551)
        - Miscellaneous Accounts: Concilium (Box 37, Folder 552)
        - International Relations #62-0034-4010 (Box 37, Folder 553)
        - Faculty Research #62-00-34-2680 (Box 37, Folder 554)
        - Faculty Research: Reginald Green #62-00-34-2685 (Box 37, Folder 555)
        - East Asian Studies #62-0034-2040 (Box 37, Folder 556)
        - Salaries Control Account #62-00-34-7050 (Box 37, Folder 557)
        - Latin American Studies #62-00-34-7055 (Box 37, Folder 558)
        - Professorships (Box 37, Folder 559)
        - Public International Law #62-00-34-7260 (Box 37, Folder 560)
        - Russian & East European Studies #62-00-34-7630 (Box 37, Folder 561)
        - Southeast Asia Studies #62-00-34-7920 (Box 37, Folder 562)
      - SAR/HEW 9396 (53-00-10-0275) (Box 37, Folder 563)
      - SDCB-Professor Lipson (62-00-10-5220) (Box 37, Folder 564)
      - treasurer's Office: Detailed Statement of Report (Box 38, Folder 565-566)
      - treasurer's Report: Printer's Schedule (Box 38, Folder 567)
      - treasurer's Reports (Box 38, Folder 568)
    - 1963-1964
      - Budget: Comparison, 1963-1964, Preliminary, 1964-1965 (Box 38, Folder 569)
      - Budget: Expenditure Accounts (Box 38, Folder 570)
      - treasurer's Office: Budget Statements, Preliminary Statements & Analysis of Differences (Box 38, Folder 571)
      - Overtime
        - Gifts, Grants, Contracts (Box 38, Folder 572)
        - Comptroller's Office (Box 38, Folder 573)
        - Budget Department (Box 38, Folder 574)
        - Accounting Department (Box 38, Folder 575)
        - Payroll Department (Box 38, Folder 576)
        - Investment Accounting (Box 39, Folder 577)
        - Inventory Control (Box 39, Folder 578)
        - IBM Department (Box 39, Folder 579)
      - treasurer's Report: Printer's Schedule (Box 39, Folder 580)
      - treasurer's Report (Box 39, Folder 581-582)
      - treasurer's Report: Detailed Statement (Box 39, Folder 583)
    - 1964-1965
      - treasurer's Office: Budget Statements, Analysis of Differences, Comparison, & Actual (Box 39, Folder 584)
      - Budget: Expenditure Accounts (Box 40, Folder 585)
      - Financial Statements: 1965 & Account's Report (Box 40, Folder 586)
      - New Chart of Accounts: 1965, Explanation of (Box 40, Folder 587-588)
      - treasurer's Report (Box 40, Folder 589-591)
      - treasurer's Report: Detailed Statement (Box 41, Folder 592)
      - Printer's Schedule: Working Papers (Box 41, Folder 593)
      - treasurer's Report: Board of Trustees of Sheffield Scientific School (Box 41, Folder 594)
    - 1965-1966
      - treasurer's Office: Budget Statements (Box 41, Folder 595)
  - Series II
    - 1897-1938
      - Ledger:, 1897-1908 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Ledger: 1908-1913, Loomis Acct., Commencement Rooms, McClung, Lee (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Old Balances, 1910-1911, 1911-1912, Various Schools, Dormitories, Dining Halls (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Ledger:, 1917-1922 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Ledger: 1922-1926, B & M Job Tickets, Miscellaneous, Clerical Bureau, Adjustments, Supplies (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Ledger: Accounts Payable & Various Accounts, Trial Balance (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 1926-1931
      - Ledger
        - Trial Balance, -1937 (Box 42, Folder 7)
        - New Haven Bank, -1934 (Box 42, Folder 7)
        - Campaign Committees, -1932 (Box 42, Folder 7)
        - Miscellaneous, -1933 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Ledger:, 1934-1936 - 1936-1938 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Ledger: 1926-1927, Receipts. & Disbursements, 1930-1937, Closing Entries, 1929-1938 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Ledger: Sundry Items - n.d. (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Ledgers & Miscellaneous Papers
      - Ledger: Canner Incorporated, 1959-1964 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - Canner Incorporated, Miscellaneous Papers (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Ledger: Canner Incorporated, 1959-1964 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Ledgers
      - Canner, Incorporated, 1959-1964 (Box 43, Folder 14)
      - Whitehall Incorporated, 1959-1964 (Box 43, Folder 15-16)
    - Whitehall Incorporated, 1959-1964 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Whitehall Incorporated, Miscellaneous Papers, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Whitehall Incorporated, Miscellaneous Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Ledger: Whitney Incorporated, 1959-1964 (Box 44, Folder 20-21)
    - Whitney Incorporated, Worksheet, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Budget Comparisons, Financial History, 1909-1973 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Yale Alumni Musical Corporation, 1922-1948
      - Loans Outstanding, Minutes, 1922-1948 (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - Loans Paid in Full, 1922-1930 (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - Loans Repaid as Gifts, 1922-1945 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Inventory, 1866-1897, tuition, Steam, Grapevine Point (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Inventory, 1934 (Box 45, Folder 28-31)
    - Inventory, 1934-1936 (Box 46, Folder 32-36)
    - 1933-1962
      - Book Prizes: Stubs, 1933-1945 (Box 46, Folder 37)
      - Car Purchases: Records, 1938-1960 (Box 46, Folder 38)
      - Xerox Contracts, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 39)
      - IBM Contracts, 1954-1956 (International Business Machines) (Box 47, Folder 40)
      - Overhead Reference: Miscellaneous, 1950-1954 (Box 47, Folder 41)
      - Tuition Contracts, Individual, Miscellaneous, 1958-1962 (Box 47, Folder 42)
      - Capital Fund Drive, Gift Memos, 1958-1963 (Box 47, Folder 43)
      - Fund Drive, Gift Memos, 1960-1961 (Box 47, Folder 44-45)
      - Fund Drive, Gift Memos, 1961-1962 (Box 47, Folder 46)
    - Fund Drive, Gift Memos
      - 1961 (Box 48, Folder 47)
      - 1962 (Box 48, Folder 48-49)
    - Year Books, 1911-1912 -- 1940-1941
      - 1911-1912 (Box 48, Folder 50)
      - Summary Account of Students, 1911-1925 (Box 48, Folder 51)
      - 1912-1925 (Box 48, Folder 52)
      - 1920-1921 (Box 49, Folder 53)
      - Yale Dining Hall, 1921 (Box 49, Folder 54)
      - 1923-1928 (Box 49, Folder 55-58)
      - 1928-1929 (Box 50, Folder 59)
      - 1929-1930, Interest on Fund & Suspense Accounts (Box 50, Folder 60)
      - 1931-1932 (Box 50, Folder 61)
      - 1931-1934, Payroll Balances (Box 50, Folder 62)
      - 1932-1933 (Box 50, Folder 63-64)
      - 1934-1936 (Box 51, Folder 65-66)
    - Class Books
      - 1936-1940 (Box 51, Folder 67-70)
    - Year Books, Payroll Balances, 1933-1934 (Box 52, Folder 71)
    - Class Books
      - 1939-1941 (Box 52, Folder 72-73)
  - Series III
    - 1 Harkness Account: Working papers, 1930-1936 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1933-1938 (Box 53, Folder 2-11)
    - Photostats, 1937-1938 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Income & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1938-1939 (Box 53, Folder 13-14)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Income & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1938-1939 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increase & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 16-17)
    - Income & Expenses, 1939-1943 (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1940-1941 (Box 54, Folder 19-21)
    - Photostats, 1940-1941 (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Income & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1941-1942 (Box 54, Folder 23-24)
    - Photostats, 1941-1942 (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Income & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1942-1943 (Box 54, Folder 26-27)
    - Income & Expenses, 1942-1946 (Box 54, Folder 28)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1943-1946 (Box 55, Folder 29-34)
    - Rate Control Cards & Purpose Control Cards, 1945-1951 (Box 55, Folder 35)
    - Purpose Control Cards, 1945-1952 (Box 55, Folder 36)
    - Balance Sheet & Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1946-1947 (Box 55, Folder 37-39)
    - Photostats, 1946-1947 (Box 55, Folder 40)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1947-1948 (Box 55, Folder 41-43)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1948-1949 (1 of 3) (Box 55, Folder 44)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1948-1949 (Box 56, Folder 45-46)
    - Case Disbursements Register, 1959-1962 (Box 56, Folder 47)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1960-1962 (Box 56, Folder 48-51)
    - Funds of Yale University, Miscellaneous Years After 1961[?] (Box 56, Folder 52-53)
    - Balance Sheet & Statement of Increases & Expenses, Description of Funds, 1962-1965 (Box 56, Folder 54-59)
- Correspondence regarding insurance, circa 1942-1943; Accession 1990-A-153
  Treasurer's Office - Johnson and Higgins Correspondence and Related Materials Regarding Yale University Insurance
  - Johnson and Higgins Correspondence and Related Materials Regarding Yale University Insurance, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Financial records, circa 1900-1930; Accession 1996-A-075
  - Accounts, 1910-1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bursar's reports, 1916-1918, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bursar's vouchers, 1915-1918, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Correspondence, 1910-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Haight, Charles C. - payments (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Invoices, 1906-1930 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 11)
  - Legal correspondence, 1915-1917, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Library receipts, 1915 December-1918 March (Box 2, Folder 13 - 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pelton, Henry C. - invoices (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Rogers, James Gamble - invoices and payments (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Receipts, 1909 May-1918 (Box 2, Folder 19 - 24)
  - Payment vouchers, 1930 May-1931 December (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - [Departmental] vouchers, 1909-1918 April (Box 2, Folder 26 - 28)
  - Vouchers
    - 1904 Jun 3-Jul 6 (Box 3)
    - 1904 Jul 7-Jul 12 (Box 4)
    - 1904 Jul 13-Jul 30 (Box 5)
    - 1907 Jan 7, 1911 Jun 30, 1904 Jun 15-Jun 29 (Box 6)
  - Invoices, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Payroll accounts, 1907-1917 (Box 7)